- Please make it in time!
(カカシ/オビト)間に合え！
- Rin!
Thank you, Rin.
Obito and I will be
joining you shortly.
(２人)リン。
We can catch up then,
the three of us together.
《カカシ : ありがとう リン。
俺もオビトも
そろそろ そっちへ行くよ。
Rin...
This time, let's spend...
また３人で ゆっくり話をしよう》
some alone time together.
Just you and me.
《オビト : リン 今度は あの世で→
Kakashi would just be in the way.
少し俺と
２人きりの時間を過ごそう》
I'll leave him here.
《カカシは邪魔だ。
ここに置いていくよ》
aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
You Better...
Why?
I thought we had both resolved to...
Your power is still needed here!
どうしてだ？
互いに覚悟はもう…。
お前の力は まだ今ここで必要だ。
We need to rebuild chakra again.
Mother, let's teleport to
the Root Time-Space...
You'll recover faster there, too.
(ゼツ)いったん チャクラを練り直しか。
Why would you do this
for someone useless like me?
Never mind that.
母さん 始球空間へ飛ぼう。
Kakashi, be wary of the enemy.
あそこなら回復も早い。
なぜ 役にも立たない俺のために？
そんなことより
敵に注意しろ カカシ。
Naruto, Sasuke, and Sakura...
This is a crucial time for them.
Kakashi, you must survive
and support the next generation.
《ナルト サスケ そして サクラか。
It's too soon for you to die.
こいつらは今 大切なときだ。
カカシ お前は
新しい世代の支えとして→
It's totally useless, Naruto.
まだ死ぬには早い》
He's a goner.
He'll rot away like trash and die.
Enough, Naruto.
(ゼツ)そんなことをしてもムダだ ナルト。
He's right.
Don't waste your chakra.
そいつはもうダメだ。
Why do you sympathize with him?
ゴミのように朽ちて死ぬ。
よせ ナルト やつの言うとおりだ。
He was originally your enemy, right?
チャクラをムダに使うな。
Then again,
he's a traitor to us now.
なぜ そんなやつに肩入れする？
A loser on both sides.
そいつは もともと
お前らの敵だった男だろ。
Hated and resented
by friend and foe alike,
まぁ かといって
こちらとしても裏切られた→
with no one to call
comrade or family...
He's alone, with nothing left.
どっちつかずのクズだがな。
敵味方双方から忌み嫌われ→
He's lost everyone precious to him,
and he can't realize his dreams.
悲しんでくれる
仲間も肉親もいない。
And after being used up,
he's helpless at the end...
そいつは独り 何も残らない。
He's a fool, filled with
nothing but mistakes...
大切な人を亡くし
夢を叶えることもできず→
You've done nothing but—!
You're right...
利用されたあげく
最後にうろうろと→
Rin... again...
失敗だらけのマヌケか。
I'll create a world where
we can be together again.
(ナルト)てめえ さっきから…。
そうだな。
((オビト : リン もう一度…。
もう一度
キミのいる世界をつくろう。
I shall...
sever the nexuses...
of this world.
《俺が この世の因果を→
断ち切る》
Now go on...
(マダラ)あ…。
Until I will be revived...
You shall be...
さぁ 動け 俺が復活するまでの間。
Who are you?
I am Madara Uchiha.
お前が…。
But a world of just
victors, peace, and love...
(長門)誰だ？
うちはマダラだ。
Such a world can be created too.
If you allow us to collaborate,
you can learn how.
勝者だけの世界
平和だけの世界 愛だけの世界。
それらだけの世界を
つくることもできる。
Let's go, Konan... Nagato.
我々が協力すれば
そのやり方を知ることができる。
We can't trust these guys!
Don't ever approach us again!
(弥彦)行くぞ 小南 長門。
こいつらは信用できない。
二度と俺たちに近づくな。
You'll eventually realize it too.
Who are you?
You are going to be
very useful to me.
お前も いずれ
気づくことになる。
RIN NOHARA
(ヤグラ)何やつだ！
お前には せいぜい
役に立ってもらうとしよう。
Summoning Jutsu!
口寄せの術！
Minato Sensei...
《ミナト先生…》
I hereby declare the start of
the Fourth Great Ninja War.
(我愛羅)あ～ あ…。
第四次忍界大戦
ここに 宣戦を布告する。
They each have formidable strength.
And I have even more
up my sleeve.
(カブト)どれも強者揃いだ。
それに 僕の持っている駒は
これだけじゃない。
So be it.
We will join forces with you.
They will know despair thoroughly.
いいだろう 手を組んでやる。
絶望を教えてやるのさ。 丁寧にな。
(みんな)うわ～！
うっ… うわっ。
(うわ～っ！))
You're right.
It's an end worthy of
the criminal that I am.
お前の言うとおり→
My Visual Prowess is back!
罪人の俺に ふさわしい最後だ。
《サスケ : 瞳力が戻った》
チッ。
We've been here before!
Did she change worlds again?!
(サクラ)ここは前に来た…。
Naruto!
また世界を変えたのか。
Naruto, I'll handle
the diversions this time.
He's beyond help.
Come with me.
ナルト！
今度は俺が陽動をかける。
そいつは もう助からん。
こっちへ来い。
I'm going on ahead!
先に行く。
Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it!
くそっ くそっ… くそ～っ！
That's enough.
Thank you, Naruto
もういい… ありがとうな ナルト。
After fighting you,
I feel like I've woken up.
(オビト)俺は お前と戦って→
You and I are both powerless shinobi.
何か目が覚めたような気がした。
You...
no, I should say everyone...
((俺も お前も
しょせん 無力な忍だ。
will eventually end up like me.
お前も…。
I'll never end up like you!
いや 誰でもいずれ→
How many times
do I have to tell you?!
My dream is to become
the Hokage!
俺のようになるのだからな。
俺は てめえみてえにはならねえ。
There is no reason to keep on
fighting for a world like this.
何度も言ってんだろ。
俺がなりてえのは火影だ！
In a few minutes,
this world will be gone anyway.
こんな世界のために→
Why do you still fight?!
もう戦う意味はないはずだ。
Because it's my Ninja Way.
この世界も数分で終わる。
I never go back on my word.
そうまでして なぜ戦う!?
まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
(それが 俺の忍道だからだ))
Don't overdo it.
Let's call it a day.
((オビト : うおぉ～！
No, I'm not giving up.
Didn't I make a promise?
うわっ！
That I'm gonna become
the Hokage!
Really...
(リン)無理しないで
今日はここまでにしよう。
It was as if I saw my past self
when I looked at you.
いや 俺は諦めねえ。
約束したろ。
俺は火影になるんだからな。
And I regret what I am now.
(もう…))
But for some reason,
it also made me happy.
まるでな お前を見ていると→
昔の自分を見ているようで
今の自分を後悔した。
As a kid, I would imagine myself
as Hokage so often.
だが 何よりそれが
なぜだか嬉しくもあってな。
That indescribable feeling
of exhilaration and anxiety...
昔 ガキの頃は何度も
火影になった自分を想像してよ。
I think you brought
that all back for me.
興奮と不安と
あの何とも言えぬ気持。
それを思い出させたからだろう。
((２人 : はっ！
Don't cry, Obito.
You'll get laughed at.
I know.
Besides, the world of shinobi
is all about fighting.
ウッ…。
泣くな オビト。
It's nowhere near
a peaceful world.
そんなザマじゃ 笑われるぞ。
And I'll put an end to it,
no matter what.
わかってる。
それに 忍の世界は争いだらけだ。
Hey, you're not the only ones.
Don't forget that we're here too.
平和な世とは程遠い。
Yeah, that's right.
そんなもの
俺が必ず終わらせてやる。
(アスマ)おい お前らだけじゃない。
Rin... I...
俺たちもいることを忘れるなよ。
ああ そうだな。
リン 俺は…。
What's that?
The higher-ups have decided.
Obito, you're going to be
the next Hokage.
But you're just as qualified...
(オビト)それは？
(カカシ)上層部の決定だよ。
A supportive role suits me better.
I'm sure Rin would say
the same thing.
オビト お前が次の火影に決まった。
だが 実力なら お前だって…。
俺は サポート役が性に合ってる。
リンだって きっとそう言うさ。
But if you screw up,
I won't hesitate
to step up as a candidate
to become the next Hokage.
What?!
Do your best!
まっ お前がヘマをしたら 容赦なく
次の火影に立候補するけどな。
RIN NOHARA
なんだと？
頑張れよ。
This is driving me crazy!
All this paperwork
day in and day out.
That can't be helped...
You're the Hokage now.
Besides, something like this
sure beats having to fight every day.
気がめいるな。
来る日も来る日も書類 書類。
しかたないだろ。
お前は火影なんだから。
That's for sure.
うへっ。
それに この程度の雑務→
It's the Hokage!
Lord Hokage! Hello!
戦いに追われる日々より
ずっとマシだ。
確かにな。
Lord Hokage,
are you on your rounds?
Well, yes.
Yeah, right!
You're just goofing off, right?
ハハッ。
火影様！
Speak for yourself!
お疲れさまです。
What?!
Wanna make something of it?
Cut it out!
火影様 見回りですか？
まあな。
とか言って ほんとは
サボってるだけじゃねえの？
Why did you hit only me?
Because you were rude
to Lord Hokage!
フン お前じゃあるまいし。
なんだと！
Seriously...
やるのか？
やめなさい！
うぁ～っ！
It's so peaceful, thanks to you.
Not just me.
It's everyone who did their best
to support the village.
って なんで
俺だけなんだってばよ！
(サクラ)だいたい
火影様に対して失礼でしょ。
It would be nice to talk
to Rin someday.
まったく お前のおかげで
平和なもんだ。
Yeah.
俺だけじゃない。
今日まで里を支えてきた→
Imagining the village, friends,
and me as the Hokage...
みんなの力があってこそだ。
(いつか リンに話せるといいな。
ああ))
Even after all that's happened...
Just the thought of it seems to
fill up the hole in my heart.
(オビト)里があり 仲間がいて
火影の俺がいると…。
Maybe it's because it's the end,
いまさらな。
I find myself rambling all of a sudden.
その想像するだけで 心の穴が
埋まっていく気がしたよ。
フッ。
Ouch!
最後だからか 俺は… 何をペラペラと。
Don't act tough and
hide your wounds.
I'm always watching you.
((イタッ！
You promised me that
you would become Hokage, Obito.
Listen, I want to stop this war too.
(リン)強がって 傷を隠しても ダメ！
ちゃんと見てんだから。
I really want to save the world.
オビトは 火影になるって
私に約束した。
So I've decided to stick by
your side and watch over you.
いい？ 私だって
この戦争を止めたい。
世界を救いたいと
本気で思ってるよ。
You told me saving you
was the same as saving
the world, remember?
だから オビトのこと そばで
しっかり見守るって決めたの。
(リン)あなたを救うことは
世界を救うのと同じなんでしょ？
Yeah!
Since I'm keeping
an eye on you,
you can't hide anything
from me anymore.
Okay! Okay!
うん…。
Go for it, Obito!
私が見張ってるってことは→
Become Hokage and show me
how you'll save the world.
もう なんにも
隠しごとはできないよ。
That's another promise!
うん！ うん！
Let's go!
頑張れ オビト！
火影になって かっこよく
世界を救うとこ 見せてね！
それも 約束だよ。
A lot more suffering
likely awaits you, Naruto.
(行こう))
But don't ever change
and hang on to your Ninja Way.
(オビト)お前には これから まだ
多くの苦しみがあるだろう。
You once told me that
never going back on your word
is your Ninja Way, right?
だが それでも
お前は変わることなく→
その忍道を貫き通せ。
Yeah...
いつか 俺に言ったな？
まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げない。
それが俺の忍道だ…。
だったかな？
あぁ。
Naruto...
You better...
become Hokage!
Yeah!
ナルト！
お前は 必ず 火影になれ。
あぁ！
The vermin traitor has
finally died, eh?
He was vermin and
persistent as a cockroach.
フッ！
(ゼツ)裏切り者の虫ケラが
やっと死んだか。
Don't laugh at Obito!
虫ケラは 虫ケラでも
このしつこさは ゴキブリだったな。
Naruto...
If you keep resisting,
ハハハハハ！
you'll end up pitifully crumbling
to ash just like him!
オビトを笑うな。
ナルト…。
As someone who tried
to become Hokage,
ナルト… お前も
これ以上 刃向かってると→
Obito is nothing but...
崩れて灰になった 哀れでみじめな
そいつと同じになるんだ。
awesome to me!
火影になろうとしたオビトは
俺には…。
Rin!
I've been waiting.
なっ！
Really?
かっこよくしか見えねえよ！
Sorry, I made you wait.
Seems you got lost along the way.
Yeah...
((リン…。
A lot of things happened
before I could come here.
待ってたよ。
(オビト)そうか。 待たせて すまねえ。
Rin, you know...
(リン)いろいろ
道に迷ったみたいだね。
that promise I made to you...
あぁ… ここに来るまで
いろいろ あってよ。
No, you did your best!
リン…。
I've been watching you all along!
俺 リンとの約束…。
ううん。
オビトは頑張ったじゃない。
Let's go!
ずっと 見てたんだよ。
(行こう))
boku ni wa wakaru nda uso o tsuite iru kimi ga
I can tell when you're lying
naite ii yo koko ni zutto irukara
It's okay to cry because I'll always be here
sekaijuu ni koborete iru hontou no ai no kimochi
Feelings of true love spills out throughout the world
sagashidashite miushinatte yoake ga kuru no matteru
We search for it but lose it, while waiting for daybreak
migi no hoshi ni wa boku no namae o tsukete
The star on the right will bear my name
kimi ga yonde okureyo
Will you call out to it?
hidari no hoshi ni wa kimi no namae ga ne
The star on the left will bear your name
niau yo zutto soba ni irukara
It's perfect, because we'll always be together
Come on, Obito.
Rin, do you mind waiting
just a little longer?
Obito?
Only a little bit before
we move on...
I'd like to make one
more detour along the way.
Really... Who do you want
to save this time?
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Sharingan Revived"
I'll be waiting, right here.